HERMIN ROBILLARD

East Bay, CA - 518.364.8628 - hermin303@gmail.com - GitHub - LinkedIn

Objective

I am a results-driven web developer with knowledge of the software lifecycle. I have a multidisciplinary background with experience in Business and Project management capable of putting emphasis on business requirements and on customer satisfaction.

Skills

Technical skills: HTML5 and CSS3, Java, JavaScript, C#, Python, MySQL, jQuery, Ruby, and Bootstrap.

Frameworks & tools: Node.js, Visual Studio, GIMP, MS Office, text editors, CLI and dev tools.

Soft skills: Project management, Business management, languages (English, Spanish, and French).

Projects

Portfolio Site [GitHub]

Aug. 2017 - Sept. 2017

- Built a fully responsive website from scratch.
- Utilized HTML5 and CSS3, GIMP, Bootstrap, web browsers, and developer tools.

Movie project [GitHub]

July. 2017 - Aug. 2017

- Used front and back end programming to display movies trailers.
- Applied Python, HTML5 and CSS3, web browsers, and developer tools.

Non-profit web site design [Portfolio]

May. 2017 - Jun. 2017

- Designed lifecycle process involved in a website's project prior to coding.
- Utilized editing tools, design tools (draw.io, MS Visio, etc.), Project management tools (MS project).

For more projects go to my portfolio here.

Work Experience

Lead & Support IT Technician, Smart Source (California).

Aug. 2017 - Present

- Participate in helpdesk support for PC, workstations, printers, and peripherals.
- Update IT systems and networks for 24 bank locations and 2 Healthcare Clinics.

Software Development Intern, Revature, Remote (Virginia).

Aug. 2016 - Aug. 2017

- Developed 1 software project with front and back-end knowledge.
- Designed a database using Java (POJO, DAO, Servlets), HTML and CSS, SQL.

Project Manager, Fondas (Venezuela).

May 2006 - Sept. 2009

- Managed 8 projects to develop products and services for 4 communities.
- Used MS Project, MS Visio, MS Office, and remote database.

IT HelpDesk, Data System (Venezuela).

Feb. 2001 - Sept. 2007

- Built and fixed 2 entire IT systems, 2 networks, and helpdesk for set-up and fix 32+ workstations.
- Tutored 4 academic projects.
- Provided translation services in French, Spanish, and English.

Education

Udacity. Nanodegree Full Stack Web Developer.

Jul. 2017 - Jul. 2018

Southern New Hampshire University. B.S. - IT w/c Software Dev (GPA: 3.70).

Oct. 2014 - Aug. 2017

Territorial Polytechnic University of Falcon Alonso Gamero (Venezuela).

Sept. 2000 - Dec. 2003

Associate degree in Business Administration.